ANGELO GONZALEZ

6723 N Ashland Ave Chicago, IL 60626 (312) 307-6448 angelogonzalez@outlook.com

AWARDS

National Hispanic Scholar

ASSOCIATIONS

ACM Alianza IEEE Sigma Phi Epsilon

LANGUAGES

English (natively fluent)
Spanish (natively fluent)

LINKEDIN

https://www.linkedin.com/in/angelogonzalez1/

PORTFOLIO

https://jello10298.github.io

PROFILE

Senior Fullstack Developer, Project Lead and Mentor with over two decades of continuous integration experience focused on agile and full software lifecycle principles of analysis, architecture, design, development, deployment and testing of more than 5,000 software solutions for clients encompassing eminent brands like Hyatt Hotels, Microsoft, United Healthcare, Domino's Pizza, Discover Card and Rolex, among others with a proven impact of 20% year-over-year revenue increase through organizational process improvements and team-based management interface accelerations.

SKILLS

- Specialized in Vi/VIM, Node, Java SE/CE/EE, JSP, Sling, Granite, OSGI, Sightly, Spring/Springboot web/jpa/acctuator/amqp, Python, PERL, PHP, Typescript, Angular, React and React Native - with an emphasis on Project Management.
- Profound knowledge of MPA (Multiple Page Applications) and SPA (Single Page Applications) integrations into CMS (Content Management Systems) and CRM (Customer Relationship Management) platforms utilizing frameworks such as Gulp, Grunt, Webpack, Bootstrap, NextJS and Springboot leveraging low-level layers such as HTML5, CSS2/CSS3, Angular, React, React Native and NextJS for static site generation/templating.
- Decades of experience developing all software layers with integrated CI/CD processes for data warehousing, middleware and frontend delivery through micro-services oriented architecture patterns utilizing 3NF (third-normal form) adherence and NoSQL data persistence, REST APIs/SOAP and component-based templates utilizing on-premise and cloud-based regions and edge computing services/technologies with built-in disaster recovery.
- Expert experience with cloud technologies such as Google Cloud, Azure and AWS including EC2, ECS, Lambda, S3, and RDS.
- Hands-on containerization expertise utilizing Kubernetes, Docker, K8, and, occasionally, RPM for deployment of applications and messaging platforms like KAFKA, Rabbit MQ, Magento, AEM, Apollo, Java EE/Tomcat, Springboot, Drupal, Wordpress, iOS, Android and other custom software solutions.
- Exceptional skills in code reviews, code versioning and CI/CD pipelines using Subversion/Git and Github Actions while setting up Jenkins, AWS and Azure CI/CD pipelines, adhering to reliable CI/CD practices using pre/post build processing, code linters, unit testing, selenium end-to-end integration testing

and gatling load/performance testing through dev/int/prod environments while ensuring high-quality local development.

- Expert experience with database design and index creation for SQL (Structured Query Language) databases utilizing 3NF (third-normal form) design patterns, debugging, maintenance and index performance tuning for terabytes of data in Oracle, Postgres, MySQL, IBM DB/2 and NCR Teradata.
- Extensive experience with NoSQL and Object Relational Mapping databases like Cassandra, CouchDB, MongoDB and Redis along with sharding experience.
- Expert experience with analytics tools integrations, delivery of software application metric reports and AI/ML integrations for long-term software improvement roadmap creation for teams and organizational steering.
- Constant evangelist of object-oriented software design using well-known design patterns and standardized protocols quickly adopted by teams and organizations.
- Prefers working with tremendously diverse teams in different time zones.

EDUCATION

Northwestern University, Master of Science Computer Information Systems w/ Data Science Specialization	2015 - 2017 Chicago, IL
Northwestern University, Bachelor of Science Computer Science - McCormick School of Engineering	1998 - 2003 Evanston, IL
	4000 4000

 Durant High School
 1996 - 1998

 GPA: 4.7 / 4.0
 Plant City, FL

National Hispanic Scholar born in Chicago, IL who started elementary school in a religious academy in Ukrainian Village, then continued into public high school in Hillsborough County, FL and was finally polished through private higher education at Northwestern University as an undergraduate in Evanston, IL and as a graduate in downtown Chicago, IL.

EXPERIENCE

Hyatt Hotels Corporation

April 2017 - April 2024

Senior Fullstack Engineer

Chicago, IL

Built over 150 custom AEM components (utilizing core AEM libraries) and Sling/ Java servlets for use by over 1,600 AngularJS micro-sites (one for each hotel) initially using Adobe Experience Manager and a SpringBoot API adaptation layer, which was later transformed into an Apollo/GraphQL service layer utilized by NextJS for the purpose of populating React/React Native components.

United Healthcare / Optum / Rally Health

April 2020 - April 2024

Senior Fullstack Engineer

Chicago, IL

(COVID-19 Illinois Initiative) Storybook-driven rewrite of an AngularJS Jenkins-based build pipeline, transforming NPM packages into React/React Native components which are scaffolded into a custom single-context React SPA, Android app, and iOS app using a GitHub Actions pipeline. Continuous security patching of NodeJS and Scala applications through CVE report monitoring.

Microsoft

May 2020 - November 2021

Senior Fullstack Contractor through Infosys

Chicago, IL

(COVID-19 Illinois Initiative) For microsoft.com store (AEM / C# / Azure platform), led several key projects. Configured AEM Sling Dynamic Includes, writing C# Rest APIs and AEM servlets while developing React components such as Product Detail Pages, central template "Buy Box" with buy button and "Remote Install to Xbox" button for xbox games. Then automated and conducted load testing with Gatling before and after successful worldwide deployment.

Vyaire

March 2020 - August 2020

Senior Fullstack Engineer through Wavicle

Chicago, IL

(COVID-19 Illinois Initiative) Developed and maintained a React Native webbased application as a proof of concept for a Fortune 500 Respirator company's executive dashboard, demonstrating capabilities in designing highlevel dashboards. Played a key role in consolidating data streams from various ERP systems from five different recent acquisitions into one streamlined reporting system, demonstrating proficiency in handling and managing large scale data. Built a Single Page Application (SPA) using ReactNative to handle report management, user access and delivery, showcasing strong experience in building SPAs. Implemented features to search all customers, open orders and material status, demonstrating strong experience with integrating data search capabilities. Developed a data entry portal for plant level manufacturing analytics input, demonstrating skills in creating efficient data entry interfaces. Created dynamic SharePoint reporting panels for live company-wide access, showing expertise in using cloud services for real-time reporting. Implemented AWS CI/CD pipelines for efficient software delivery, highlighting proficiency in DevOps practices. Collaborated effectively with a diverse team spread across different time zones, demonstrating solid team collaboration and communication skills. In addition, experience in working with onshore/offshore staffing model.

Valtech

November 2016 - April 2017

Senior Fullstack Engineer

Chicago, IL

Lead developer for various Adobe Experience Manager (AEM)-based projects for clients including Hyatt, Rolex and Lundbeck.

Senior Fullstack Engineer

Chicago, IL

Served as a technical lead to a team of 6-10 developers, employing an Agile methodology with bi-weekly sprints. Facilitated coaching sessions, computer science challenges, and regular code reviews to boost team engagement and productivity. Administered AWS compute services such as EC2, ECS, and Lambda to maintain dynamically deployed, scalable containers, demonstrating proficiency in cloud-based DevOps practices. Leveraged Jenkins to establish a continuous integration environment, reinforcing an effective CI/CD pipeline aligning with organizational goals. Performed a significant overhaul of a LAMPbased Magento middleware, simplifying its architecture to facilitate component-level modifications by junior developers, demonstrating experience in full-stack development and team mentoring. Implemented a machine learning algorithm to prioritize search results, displaying competence in AI/ML application development. Developed an iOS e-commerce application using Objective-C, incorporating a native custom checkout experience by extending and optimizing Magento REST API, further showcasing skills in mobile app development and API management.

Previous Employment

September 1998 - December 2015

Senior Fullstack Engineer

Chicago, IL

Employment information from 1998 - 2015 is available upon request, which covers the following brands/companies:

Full Time Employee

- · Abercrombie & Fitch
- · Discover Card
- · Northwestern University

Contractor

- Ability Lab (formally Rehabilitation Institute of Chicago)
- American Imaging Management
- AT&T
- · Case/New Holland
- · Domino's Pizza
- Firestone with advertising agency Two x Four
- Lightbank